{
    "id": "598f18d1122e477aa66e9e3864bb71bd",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I will follow you wherever you ……………………….",
            "description": "When both clauses refer to the future, we use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to future. ",
            "answers": [
                "will go",
                "go",
                "goes",
                "went"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I knew she ………………………. right.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too will usually be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We …………………………. them next year.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about pre-planned future events. ",
            "answers": [
                "visit",
                "are visiting",
                "have been visiting"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Does she know what …………………………..?",
            "description": "In indirect questions, the verb goes after the subject. ",
            "answers": [
                "she is doing",
                "is she doing",
                "does she do",
                ""
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He will lose his job if he ……………………….. another deadline.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "miss",
                "misses",
                "will miss"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "How soon ……………………….. you know your holiday dates?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "do",
                "will",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………………….. to come with me.",
            "description": "When there is no time reference, the present perfect is usually used to give news. ",
            "answers": [
                "has agreed",
                "have agreed",
                "has agree"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We …………………………… away anything useful.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about facts, habits etc.",
            "answers": [
                "do not throw",
                "does not throw",
                "have not throw"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………… swimming yesterday,",
            "description": "When we say when something happened, we use the simple past. ",
            "answers": [
                "went",
                "was going",
                "had gone"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………….. a boutique in the town.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "has opened",
                "has open",
                "is opened"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "They never found out what …………………………. to him.",
            "description": "Either simple past or past perfect can be used here. ",
            "answers": [
                "happened",
                "had happened",
                "has happened"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My grandfather is eighty but he still …………………………. good health.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "enjoy",
                "is enjoying",
                "enjoys"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}